Alfred I. Hallowell Papers 1892-1981 Mss.Ms.Coll.26
American Philosophical Society
- Series VI - Photographs
  - Subseries A. Berens River Ojibwa Album, 1930s; Copy: 338 photos
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, girl, [1930s] [1938?]; A110
      [Shabwon? -- J. Brown 3/90.] [No proof--probably not -- J. Brown 12/92.] [Different photo series- neg E183-1 (others are A4 series)- which may argue for being Shabwon - M. Matthews 4/12]
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids. Joe Keeper & his wife Naabap and daughter Echine, [1930s]; A111
      Naabap Keeper (Mary Jane, wife of Joe Keeper, born 1908, still living 1992), daughter Echine (Hanna, married a Green, died September 1988, Red Lake), Joe Keeper (Neapiihtank). This photograph was taken in Little Grand Rapids, Manitoba, Canada.
      Keeper, Joe; Keeper, Naabap, Mary Jane; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Naabap Keeper, [1930s]; A112
      p. 55. in Hallowell Berens River Album. Naabap Keeper, wife of Joe Keeper. This photograph was taken in Little Grand Rapids, Manitoba, Canada.
      Keeper, Naabap, Mary Jane; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Opashensh Keeper, [1930s]; A113
      p. 56 of Hallowell's Berens River Album. Opashensh is the wife of Kiiwiich Keeper.
      See also: A114, F93
      Keeper, Opashensh, 1866-1945; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Kiiwiich & Opashensh, [1930s]; A114
      p. 56, Hallowell Album. See also: A113, A115, F93
      Keeper, Kiiwiich, Alex, 1863-1944; Keeper, Opashensh, 1866-1945; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Kiiwiich, [1930s]; A115
      p. 56, Hallowell Album. See also: A114, F93
      Keeper, Kiiwiich, Alex, 1863-1944; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Ketigash Keeper, [1930s]; A116
      Ketigash Keeper [also Ketakaash]. "A councilor of the Little Grand Rapids band". P. 57 in Hallowell's Berens River Album. See also: F53
      Keeper, Ketigash; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, family [Noochipine?], [1930s]; A117
      Family group, Noochipine and his wife and three children. See also: F72. Photo Little Grand Rapids, Manitoba, Canada.
      Noochipine; Ojibwa children--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, boy, [1930s]; A118
      See also: F74
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, man and woman, [1930s]; A119
      p. 58 in Hallowell's Berens River Album. Seated in front of Waabano lodge.
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, James Keeper son of Kiiwiich, [1930s] [1938?]; A120
      James Keeper [John James Keeper - M. Matthews 4/12] p. 59 in Hallowell Berens River Album. Photo in Little Grand Rapids, Manitoba, Canada. See also A107.
      Keeper, John James; Ojibwa Indians; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Aamoo, son of John Duck, [1930s] [1938?]; A121
      p. 59 of Hallwell Berens River Album. Aamo means 'bee'. Aamo is the son of John Duck =, medicine man. Photo Little grand Rapids, Manitoba, Canada.
      Duck, Aamoo; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Waapihkwe (Mary Jane) Keeper, [1930s] [1938?]; A122
      Waabikwe, 'she has gray hair'. Mary Jane (Keeper) Leveque, married to Joe Leveque. See also: F54
      Leveque, Waapihkwe (Mary Jane Keeper); Ojibwa children--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Adam Keeper and his wife, [1930s] [1938?]; A123
      p. 60 in Hallowell's Berens River Album. Photo taken at Little Grand Rapids, Manitoba, Canada.
      Keeper, Adam; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Maamaan Duck, 1933; A124
      This is Maamaan Duck as a teenager, taken on one of Hallowell's early trips upriver. in 1932 or 33 See A125 for photo of Maamaan in 1940. Photo taken at Little Grand Rapids, Manitoba, Canada.
      Duck, Maamaan; Ojibwa children--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Maamaan Duck son of John Duck, [1930s] [1938?]; A125
      p. 61 of Hallowell's Berens River Album. Maamaan Duck is the eldest son of Jphn Duck, medicine man of Little Grand Rapids. Photo Little Grand Rapids, Manitoba, Canada. See also A124.
      Duck, Maamaan; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Kaapiskwaamaach, [1930s] [1938?]; A126
      Kaapiskwaamaach. p. 62 of Hallowell's Berens River Album. Photo taken in Little Grand Rapids, Manitoba, Canada. See also: A127
      Kaapiskwaamaach; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Kaapiskwaamaach, [1930s] [1938?]; A127
      See also: A126
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Pachiish, [1930s]; A128
      p. 63 of Hallowell's Berens River Album. Photo taken in Little Grand Rapids, Manitoba, Canada. See also A129.
      Paachiish; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Back row: 1. 2. Pachiish 3. Joseph Green 4. Joseph's wife, [1930s]; A129
      Family of Joseph Green. Back row left to right 1. [poss. wife of Paachiish - M.Matthews 4/12], 2. Paachiish, 3. Joseph Green, 4. Josephs's wife, 5. ... p. 64 of Hallowell's Berens River Album. Photo taken in Little Grand Rapids, Manitoba, Canada. Photographer: Sgt. Putnam
      Green, Ginoozhewinini (Joseph); Paachiish; Ojibwa children--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, boys, shooting bows and arrows, [1930s]; A130
      Two boys shooting bows and arrows. Photo taken in Little Grand Rapids, Manitoba, Canada.
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Noochipine and family, [1930s]; A131
      Noochipine and family, wife, two boys and two girls. He later became the first chief of the Little grand rapids band. See also: A132, A133, A134
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Noochipine, [1930s]; A132
      Noochipine later became the first chief of the Little Grand Rapids band. See also: A133, A134, A131. Photo taken in Little Grand Rapids, Manitoba, Canada.
      Noochipine; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Religion; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Noochipine, [1936?]; A133
      Chief of the Little Grand Rapids Band. See also: A132, A134, A131
      Noochipine; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Noochipine, Chief, & family, [1930s] [1936?]; A134
      Noochipine, Chief, and his family,his wife and three boys. p. 65 of Hallowell's Berens River Album. Photo taken in Little Grand Rapids, Manitoba, Canada. See also: A132, A133, A131
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Shinishkaank and wife, Waapishiink, [1930s]; A135
      Shinishkaank (John) Leveque (wearing Councillor's coat) and his wife Waaphishiink, dau of John Duck, seated in front of a waabano lodge. p. 66 of Hallowell's Berens River Album. Photo taken in Little Grand Rapids, Manitoba, Canada. Shinishkaank was born in 1872 and died in 1953.
      Leveque, Shinishkaank (John), 1872-1953; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Religion; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Shinishkaank (John Leveque), [1940?]; A136
      Leveque, Shinishkaank (John), 1872-1953; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Piimiichikaak or Aakaat, son of Noochipine, [1930s]; A137
      p. 66
      Piimiichikaak; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, wife of Minwewekaneyaash, [1930s]; A138
      Wife of Minwewekaneyaash. See also A139. P. 67 of Hallowell's Berens River Album. Photo taken in Little Grand Rapids, Manitoba, Canada.
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Minwewekaneyaash & wife, [1930s]; A139
      Minwewekanwyaash and his wife. p. 67 of Hallowell's Berens River Album. Photo taken in Little Grand Rapids, Manitoba, Canada.
      Minwewekaneyaash; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Ochikomish, [1930s]; A140
      p. 68,
      Ochikomish; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Miskwimin, [1930s]; A141
      Miskwimin. p. 68 of Hallowell's Berens River Album. Photo taken in Little Grand Rapids, Manitoba, Canada.
      Miskwimin; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Kookam & Ochikomish, sisters, [1930s]; A142
      Kookam and Ochikomish, sisters, p. 69 of Hallowell's Berens River Album. Photo taken in Little Grand Rapids, Manitoba, Canada. See also A144.
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, child in tikanagan, [1930s]; A143
      CHild in tikanagan/moss bag
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Ochikomish and young woman with two children, [1930s]; A144
      Ochikomish [or Anii?] with young woman and two children. p. 69 of Hallowell's Berens River Album. Photo taken in Little Grand Rapids, Manitoba, Canada. See also A 142.
      Ochikomish; Ojibwa children--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Nitaponaakos, David Eaglestick's father, [1930s]; A145
      Nitapnaakos, father of David Eaglestick. p. 70 of Hallowell's Berens River Album. Photo taken in Little Grand Rapids, Manitoba, Canada.
      Nitaponaakos; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, two young men, [1930s] [1938?]; A146
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, woman and child by tent, [1930s] [1938?]; A147
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, woman in front of tent, [1930s] [1938?]; A148
      p. 71of Hallowell's Berens River Album. Photo taken in Little Grand Rapids, Manitoba, Canada.
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Mahkwemot, [1930s]; A149
      Mahkwemot (Speak like a Bear). See also A150. p. 72 of Hallowell's Berens River Album. Photo taken in Little Grand Rapids, Manitoba, Canada.
      Mahkwemot; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Kitahk and Mahkwemot, [1930s]; A150
      People left to right, Kitahk (daughter of Makwemot), Makwemot. p. 72 of Hallowell's Berens River Album. Photo taken in Little Grand Rapids, Manitoba, Canada. See also A 149.
      Mahkwemot; Ojibwa children--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, afterbirth hung up in tree, 1934; A151
      After-birth hung up in tree
      Ojibwa children--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Medicine; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, young woman, [1930s] [1938?]; A152
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Joseph Green (Ginoozhewinini) & family, [1930s]; A153
      Joseph Green (Ginoozhewinini) & family, wife and four children. See also A131. p. 73 of Hallowell's Berens River Album. Photo taken in Little Grand Rapids.
      Green, Ginoozhewinini (Joseph); Ojibwa children--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, boys swimming, [1930s]; A154
      Boys swimming. See also: A155, A156, F55
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, boys swimming, [1930s]; A155
      Boys swimming. See also: A154, A156, F55
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, boys swimming, [1930s]; A156
      Boys swimming. See also: A154, A155, F55
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, campsite, [1930s]; A157
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, campsite fire, [1930s]; A158
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, campsite fire, [1930s]; A159
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Shoowap, 2nd wife of Ketigaash, [1930s]; A160
      Shoowap, 2nd wife of Ketigash Keeper. Making a rabbit skin blanket. See also: A103, A161, A162
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Shoowap, 2nd wife of Ketikash Keeper, [1930s]; A161
      Shoowap, 2nd wife of Ketigash Keeper. Making a rabbit skin blanket. See also: A103, A160, A162
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Shoowap, 2nd wife of Ketigash Keeper, [1930s]; A162
      Shoowap, 2nd wife of Ketigash Keeper. Making a rabbit skin blanket. See also: A103, A160, A161.
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, ceremonial grounds, Dream Dance, [1930s]; A163
      Preparation for Dream Dance Ceremonies. p. 78 of Hallowell's Berens River Album. Photo taken in Little Grand Rapids, Manitoba, Canada. See also A164, A165, A166, A167, A168, A169, A170.
      Ojibwa dance; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Music; Ojibwa Indians--Religion; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, ceremonial grounds with Dream drum and Ketigash Keeper drumming., [1930s]; A164
      Preparation for Dream Drum Ceremonies. Drum and drummer (Ketigash Keeper). p. 78 of Hallowell Berens River Album. Photo taken in Little Grand Rapids. See also A163, A165, A166, A167, A168, A169, A170.
      Keeper, Ketigash; Ojibwa dance; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Music; Ojibwa Indians--Religion; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, ceremonial grounds, Dream dance, [1930s]; A165
      Preparation for Dream Dance Ceremonies. Photo taken in Little Grand Rapids. A163, A164, A166, A167, A168, A169, A170
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, preparation for Dream Dance, [1930s]; A166
      Preparations for Dream Dance Ceremonies. Photo taken in Little Grand Rapids. S.ee also A163, A164, A165, A166, A167, A168, A169, A170
      Keeper, Ketigash; Keeper, Kiiwiich, Alex, 1863-1944; Ojibwa children--Canada; Ojibwa dance; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Music; Ojibwa Indians--Religion; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, preparation for Dream Dance Ceremony, [1930s]; A167
      Preparation for Dream Dance Ceremonies. On left, Ketigash Keeper, No shirt, Kiiwiich Keeper. Note eagles on poles. p. 79 of Hallowell Berens River Album. Photo taken in Little Grand Rapids. See also: A163, A164, A165, A166, A168, A169, A170, F141.
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Ketigash Keeper, Dream Dance Ceremony, [1930s]; A168
      Ketigash Keeper drumming. Dream Dance Ceremonies. Note: Eagles hanging from the poles. See also A163, A164, A165, A166, A167, A169, A170.
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids. Dream Dance Ceremony, Women dancing, [1930s]; A169
      Dream Dance Ceremonies, Little Grand Rapids. Women dancing, note: dance capes. Kiiwiich Keeper (no shirt) in distance. See also: A170, A171
      Keeper, Kiiwiich, Alex, 1863-1944; Ojibwa dance; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Music; Ojibwa Indians--Religion; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Dream Dance Ceremony, Women dancing, [1930s]; A170
      Dream Dance Ceremonies. Women dancing, includes Nenawin (Maggie) Duck, Shoowap, the wife of Noochipine, and Naabap. Photographed in Little Grand Rapids. See also: A163, A164, A165, A166, A167, A168, A169, A171.
      Keeper, Naabap, Mary Jane; Keeper, Shoowap; Nenawan, Duck, (Maggie), ca.1917; Ojibwa dance; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Music; Ojibwa Indians--Religion; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Dream Dance, Women dancers, [1930s]; A171
      Dream Dance Ceremonies. Women dancers. Left to right 1. Nenawin (Maggie) Duck, 2.Shoowap, 3., 4. wife of Noochipine, 5. Naabap. Photographed in Little Grand Rapids. See also: A169, A170
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Kiiwiich's Dream drum in front of tent and log house., [1930s]; A172
      Dream drum in front of tent and log house at Little Grand Rapids. [The square ceremonial site in the foreground probably relates to the Drum Dance that Kiiwiich recieved in a gift dream -- J. Brown 2/96]. (See Hallowell 1955, 160-163).
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Ceremonial pipe, [1930s]; A173
      Long spiral pipe stem and fairly plain pointed black stone pipe bowl. [Kiiwiich? -- M.Matthews 4/12]
      Keeper, Kiiwiich, Alex, 1863-1944; Ojibwa dance; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Religion; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Man carrying big drum, 1936; A174
      Preparation for ceremonies. Man carrying big drum. Photo taken in Little Grand Rapids. See also: A176
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Ceremony, 1936; A175
      Ceremonies
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Ceremony, 1936; A176
      See also: A175
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Sweat Lodge, [1930s]; A177
      Ceremonies. Sweat Lodge. See also: F137
      Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Medicine; Ojibwa Indians--Religion; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, building sweat lodge, [1930s]; A178
      Building Sweat Lodge.
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, building sweat lodge, [1930s]; A179
      Building sweat lodge.
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, sweat lodge, no cover, two men, [1930s]; A180
      Sweat lodge, no covers, two men. p. 84 of Hallowell's Berens River Album. Photographed in Little Grand Rapids.
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, waabano lodge of John Duck, [1930s]; A181
      Waabano lodge belonging to John Duck. Photographed in Little Grand Rapids, Manitoba, Canada. See also A 182.
      Duck, John; Ojibwa dance; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Medicine; Ojibwa Indians--Religion; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, John Duck., [1930s]; A182
      John Duck and his Waabano pavilion. p. 85 of Hallowell's Berens River Album. Photographed in Little Grand Rapids. See also A181.
      Duck, John; Ojibwa dance; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Music; Ojibwa Indians--Religion; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Waabano lodge, [1930s]; A183
      Waabano lodge, Little Grand Rapids. See also: A184, A185
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Waabano lodge, [1930s]; A184
      See also: A183, A185
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Waabano lodge, [1930s]; A185
      Waabano lodge, Little Grand Rapids, Manitoba, Canada. See also: A183, A184
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, older man seated, [1930s] [1938?]; A186
      p. 87 of Hallowell's Berens River Album. [possibly "Older brother" - friend of Omishoosh (Charlie George) Owen - M. Matthews 4/12]
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Waabano pavilion, [1930s]; A187
      Waabano pavilion. See also A188.
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Waabano pavilion, [1930s]; A188
      Waabano pavilion. See also A187.
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, constructing a shaking tent - setting upright poles., [1930s]; A189
      Constructing a shaking tent (conjuring lodge) - setting upright poles. See also: A190, A191, A192, A193
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, constructing a shaking tent, binding horizontal poles., [1930s]; A190
      Constructing a shaking tent (Conjuring Lodge) - binding horizontal poles. See also: A189, A191, A192, A193
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, constructing shaking tent, pole structure complete, [1930s]; A191
      Constructing a shaking tent (Conjuring Lodge ) - pole structure complete. See also: A189, A190, A192, A193
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, shaking tent with canvas and birch bark covers, [1930s]; A192
      Shaking tent (Conjuring Lodge) with birch bark and canvas covers. See also: A189, A190, A191, A193
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, shaking tent complete., [1930s]; A193
      Shaking tent (Conjuring Lodge) complete at Little Grand Rapids. See also: A189, A190, A191, A192
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Pauingassi, shaking tent frame, [1930s]; A194
      Conjuring Lodge (shaking tent) frame. See also: A195
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Pauingassi, shaking tent frame, [1930s]; A195
      Shaking tent (Conjuring Lodge) frame. See also: A194
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, view of settlement from the water, 1933; A196
      This view of Pauingassi from the water shows the one log house at Pauingassi at the time, a group of waaginoan dwellings and the round dream dance pavilion of Naamiwan (John) Owen. Hallowell spelled this community name as Pauingessi.
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi settlement, view across narrows., [1933?]; A197
      View of Pauingassi from grassy hilltop looking toward the far shore across the narrows. See waaginoganan with attached tents and stove pipes and the corner of a log house.
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, white dog tethered, 1933; A198
      white dog tethered to pole on grassy hill at Pauingassi.
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi; Wabano lodge, side view with flag, 1933; A199
      This is the large waabano pavilion of Naamiwan (John) Owen seen from the side with flag above. Pauingassi.
      Owen, Aankus, (Angus); Owen, Naamiwan, (John) Fair Wind; Ojibwa dance; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Medicine; Ojibwa Indians--Religion; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Oshkaabewisag and Oshkaabewisikweg (Apprentices) in front of Naamiwan's Waabano lodge, 1933; A200
      Oshkaabewisag (apprentices) and Oshkabewisikweg (female apprentices) for the ceremonial group in Pauingassi. They are photographed in front of the Waabanoowigamig, the lodge where the Waabanoo ceremony takes place. Left to right - Front row: Zaagijiwe (Charlie Moose) Owen, Asemaa, Omooday, Wewaanj. Middle row: Anang (Mary Anne) Keeper, Aminigiizhigong, A'aasii, Odaab ('everlasting woman'), Waagiginiigan (daughter of Thompson Keeper), Wewezhi'o. Back row: Maadoz, Omishoosh (Charlie George) Owen, Moonzogimaa, Boozhi (Bouchey) Pascal, Gisawenaan, Jiibay, Es (Jacob) Owen. Note: flag atop lodge and the carved bird, bineshiishikaan, on a post guarding the lodge.
      Keeper, Anang, (Mary Anne); Keeper, Waagidiniigan; Owen, Es, (Jacob); Owen, Omishoosh, (Charlie George); Owen, Zaagajiwe, (Charlie Moose); Pascal, Boozhi, (Bouchey); Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Medicine; Ojibwa Indians--Music; Ojibwa Indians--Religion; Ojibwa Indians--Social life and customs; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Ogichidaag and Ogichidaakweg (Warriors) in front of Naamiwan's Waabano lodge, 1933; A201
      Ogichidaag (Warriors) and Ogichidaakweg (Warrior women) who conducted Waabano, dream dance and other ceremonies in Pauingassi, Manitoba, Canada. Left to right - Back row: 1. Gichii Omoosonii (Chiip), 2. Niizhiishaan (James Bearhair) Owen, 3. Kiichiis (Alex) Pascal, 4. Miskwaadezi Oshkiishik (Moses) Owen, 5. Wechanimaash, (James) Owen (son of Naamiwan), Aankus (Angus) Owen (eldest son of Naamiwan). Middle row: 1. Kaapech (2nd wife of Alex Owen), 2. Maanaadis (daughter of Naamiwan, married to William Pascal), 3. Waawaak (Gichi Omoosonii's 2nd wife), 4. Giichiimookoman (Alice) Owen (wife of Moses Owen), 5. Tekis (Margaret) Pascal, Alex Pascal's 2nd. wife, Maa'aanjoosh (Lillian) Owen (wife of James Owen), Miskwa'o (Red Bird) Owen, wife of Angus Owen). Bottom row: 1. Waanachense (Alex) Owen (father of Omishoosh (Charlie George) Owen, 2. Wisaakejaak (William) Pascal (father of Alex Pascal), Ahkaakochiis (Shawtail) Owen father of Charlie Moose Owen). Boy to the left is Ochiip (David) Owen born in 1927. Information thanks to Henry Neufeld 5/93.
      Owen, Aankus, (Angus); Owen, Ahkaakochiis, (Shawtail); Owen, Kaapech; Owen, Miskwa'o, (Red Bird); Owen, Niizhishaan, (James Bearhair); Owen, Waanachense, (Alex); Owen, Wechaanimaash, (James); Pascal, Maanaadis, (Elizabeth, ne Owen); Ojibwa children--Canada; Ojibwa dance; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Medicine; Ojibwa Indians--Music; Ojibwa Indians--Religion; Ojibwa Indians--Social life and customs; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, three women in front of Waabano lodge, 1933; A202
      Waabano lodge. Women left to right: 1. A'aasii, 2. Tekis (Margaret) Pascal, 3. girl. Note drum hanging at the top of the lodge - as in lodges in Little Grand Rapids.
      Ojibwa dance; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Medicine; Ojibwa Indians--Music; Ojibwa Indians--Religion; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, healing poles, [1930s]; A203
      This photograph is of poles which were part of a healing ceremony described by Omishoosh (Charlie George) Owen and conducted by his grandfather Naamiwan and uncle Aankus.
      Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Medicine; Ojibwa Indians--Music; Ojibwa Indians--Religion; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Naamiwan (John) Owen, 'Fair Wind' [(1841?-1944) -- J. Brown], [1930s] [1938?]; A204